how to do trading in 2025 for beginners
even intermediate and advanced well I
did about a 4-Hour video about a year
ago where I literally taught you how to
trade from Z to 100 but this is a much
more simplified version from that 4H
hour long video and I want you to learn
today fast quick and easy because
truthfully who the [__] wants to watch a
4H hour video nobody nobody has time for
that we want to learn today and make
money today that's exactly what this
video is about and the importance of
that is I'm going to show you the things
that you only need in the last video I
wasted a lot of time telling you the
stuff that you don't need and I probably
overwhelmed you for no reason in this
video going to see exactly what you need
to take a trade alongside with me
together right now on this video we're
going to take a trade together and I can
almost guarantee you that by the end of
the time you watch this video that trade
is in profit because this 2025 tutorial
is about to be crazy so welcome to the
no [__] trading and welcome to how
to become a beginner Trader in 20251
for all so we do have to start at some
point which is what is Forex what is
this Currency Exchange Market why is
everybody flexing profits flying in
private jets and having supercars well
the Foreign Exchange Market is literally
everywhere all around the world every
single country participates in the
Foreign Exchange Market if there's a
country with a currency they are already
involved in the currency exchange where
money is transferring from One bank to
the other being exchanged from one
currency to the with other currency and
this is a $6.3 trillion Market every
single day this is a whole lot bigger
than the Stock Exchange Market by a mile
and a lot bigger than the crypto Market
the Foreign Exchange Market is by far
the biggest Market that moves the most
amount of money and has the most
opportunity to make money other than any
other Market out there that's why
there's so many people flexing profits
making money trading Forex so the way it
works is that you're basically
exchanging one currency for the other so
it's like let's say you exchanging money
to buy a house or you're exchanging a
car to buy another car you're exchanging
one thing for the another but you're
actually doing it with real currency the
euro versus the Japanese Yen the
Japanese yen versus the Canadian dollar
the pound versus the dollar the list
goes on forever but the key is that you
are never actually exchanging one
currency for the other you're never
turning your USD into Euro and then
turning the euro into the Japanese Yen
that's not how you make money trading
Forex you make money trading Forex
betting that one currency is going to
get stronger than the other it's a lot
simpler than owning shares or owning
different type of currencies all around
the world because truthfully that would
just be a mess and make this process
very hard you're just betting that one
currency is going to get stronger or
weaker compared to the other currency on
a shortterm medium-term or long-term
gain so as you're betting that one
currency is going to get stronger than
the other for for example Euro USD let's
say you buy EUR USD doesn't mean that
you're buying the Euro and selling the
dollar you're just predicting that the
Euro will get stronger than the dollar
or if you are selling Euro USD doesn't
mean you are selling the Euro and then
buying the dollar You're simply just
betting that the dollar is going to get
stronger than the Euro and the way you
make money here is the market is going
to move in whatever Direction and
there's going to be other people
involved in the the other direction so
if you bet $100 that it's going to go up
somebody around the world whether it's a
broker an individual Trader a retail
Trader an institution they have that
same liquidity in the market keep in
mind this is a $6.6 trillion Market I
can guarantee you every single time you
go place a trade in the market there is
somebody on the opposite side of that
market with that same exact money so if
I buy EUR USD and you sell EUR USD one
of us is going to make money because the
market has to go up or it has to go down
and whenever the market goes into either
or of our favor whenever we close out we
get the profit from that other Trader
institution retail Trader that they have
Place into the market you're not
actually taking it out of their accounts
but it's just inside of this Cloud where
all of this $6.6 trillion is being moved
every single day and now don't worry if
this sounds a little too complex don't
worry later throughout this video I'm
going to literally take a trade with you
I'm going to show you how I put the
money into the market how we take a
trade how we take the money out of the
market and then we take the money from
the broker then we take it to our bank
account it's a very simple process
everything should take about 5 to 10
minutes so in order for you to execute
these trades and you determine if you
want to buy a market or sell a market
you have to be looking at a chart these
are these charts that go up and down and
you see everybody posting and truthfully
this probably looks like it's Chinese to
you and you don't understand what the
hell is going on here well I'm here to
tell you I don't speak Chinese and I
understand these things better than I
understand my girlfriend this I have a
better relationship than I have with my
girlfriend and so can you and it's very
easy and I'm going to show you how to do
that now that we are here on the markets
what I did in the last video is I wasted
a lot of time explaining to you the
things that I do not use on this
platform and I broke them down and
explained them in detail for truthfully
no reason I'm going to explain to you
exactly what I use inside of this
platform everything else that I don't
explain I do not use and is total
[__] it is not necessary the best
example and analogy that I can give you
on this is like your car you get into
your car and I'm sure your car has a
bunch of buttons and a bunch of settings
and a bunch of different [__] that you
truthfully never use what you care about
is when you turn on the car the steering
wheel works the brake on the accelerator
the AC and the stereo system if all that
is good you're going to get to your
destination perfectly this is exact same
thing here there's a lot of extra things
here that are not needed all I care
about is what the price is being
reflected that my Wicks are on point and
some of the tools that I need to draw up
the drawings on the chart for it to make
sense and you don't need to understand
absolutely everything on this platform
to make money trading be profitable or
even understand how to use this platform
so let's get right into it as soon as
you create your account on trading view
you're going to go in here and you're
going to add a pair simplest way to add
a pair is you type up any pair for
example let's say Euro USD as soon as
you click EUR USD you can go and click
on it and as you're going to see how the
chart will pop up if you want to add it
to your watch list for whatever reason
is the currency per you want to add you
hover over this flag and then you just
simply tap it and then you put whatever
color on which section you want to put
on it that section will pop up in this
section here here's where you're going
to have all your different types of
currency pairs all different types of
symbols cryptos stocks anything that has
a charts will be able to be added here
onto your watch list you can split your
watch list by colors each color that you
add can signify something for you
truthfully I have everything blue keep
all my markers in the same spot I watch
them all the time and it it's a lot
better than constantly having to go to
different folders to look for them in
here as you can tell I have a lot of
different markets added because I trade
a lot of different markets and I'm
always looking for new opportunities to
make money in the markets because when
one market is moving choppy I go and and
move on to another one if you stay just
watching One Market the market could be
choppy for days weeks months and you're
limiting your opportunity to execute a
profitable strategy on a market that is
giving you a great trade setup that is
having great trending moves and so on so
once you add all of your currency paers
to your watch list once again say I want
to add
gbpusd you add gbpusd you click on the
color option here or you click on the
chart and you're going to notice how
gbpusd will pop up right here for
whatever reason you want to take it out
you can just click the little Trash
button or you can just click the color
option right here and then it will
remove it from your watch list aside
from that everything else in here other
than the symbol I don't know what the
hell this means I don't know what this
means or this means none of this means
anything to me obviously I understand
it's what the price is at that point but
for me I rather just go to the chart and
see how it's being reflected I don't
need to look at the numbers I like to
look at the charts the numbers don't get
tell me anything the charts tell me
everything aside from that on the top
over here you have a couple buttons
which I never use any of these buttons
here the alarms is the only section
where I actually dive a little bit
deeper in because if I am waiting for a
trade to reach a certain point but I'm
going to be at the gym I'm going to be
out on the road and I'm not in my
computer actively watching the markets I
set on the alarm and the alarm notifies
me like if it was a phone call Market
literally calls me and says hey letting
you know trade is here doesn't actually
call you it's just an alarm that
notifies you that the market is at that
point so if you want to place an alarm
it's very simple you just go here onto
the chart you're going to get this
little plus sign right here soon as you
click on it you can click ADD alert and
then you're going to see how you're
going to have an active alert and it'll
be here pending on the chart for
whatever reason you want to go and you
want to remove it you click here the
garbage can sure you want to delete it
it deletes it for you this is the
history of all of my alarms and I'm
going tell you right now I got a lot
more excited when the market calls me
than my girlfriend to place as many
alarms as you want gives you a lot
better feeling and it doesn't complain
and it makes you money I think it's
great aside from that I don't know what
the hell this is I don't know what this
is and I don't know what this is here I
don't associate myself with any of these
other sections other than just where my
currency pair list is on top over here
you're going to have your basic back
button so let's say that you draw
something and for whatever reason you go
ahead and then you delete it you want it
back click this goes right back pretty
straightforward replay button this is if
you want to back test you go to this
point in the charts and if you want to
replay it you can click down here the
market will go ahead and play itself and
it will be able to give you an idea of
how you back test but personally I am
very against back testing testing I
don't think back testing is good for any
Trader I actually think back testing
does damage to Traders I think it
creates this false expectation of how
the market is going to move and the fact
that you can see what you just erased
it's kind of like you're cheating it's
like you're going to take a test you're
going to look at the answers and then
you're going to take the test how the
[__] does that make any sense take right
now all right tell me what happened when
the market got here what you you just
saw it you just erased it yourself so to
me it's a form of cheating and again for
this to happen on this move this Market
took exactly
about about 7 days you're going to play
7 Days of the market in 15 seconds that
is very unrealistic and it's really bad
for your mental psychology because what
you're doing is you're creating this
false expectation that the market is
going to move that fast the hardest part
of being a Trader is sitting on your
hands whether it's before entering a
trade or while you are in a trade and
back testing messes all of that up so I
don't ever recommend to do it this is
another section for the alarms can type
up the currency pair put the price and
basically create it for me I never use
this option I always go to the Chart
directly and I just click this plus sign
wherever I want to add the alarm this
button I've never used it indicators is
only necessary if you want to add
indicators I personally the only have
one indicator and I use the 50 EMA so my
input is 50 source is close offset zero
method SMA and length is 50 this is the
only EMA that I use and truthfully this
does not make or break any trades for me
so this 50 EMA does not determine if I
should enter a trade or not it is
literally just an added Confluence to
give you a perspective on how important
this is to me like if you're going to go
buy a car and they say that they're
going to wash the car for you put tire
shine and they give you free gas that
does not mean you're going to buy the
car because of that it just sweetens up
the deal a little bit the exact same
thing here the EMA sweetens up the trade
that I'm going to be interested in
taking following that in this section
here you can see that we have all these
different types of way on how the market
could be seen you can see the market in
this different type of format other than
candlesticks we have these box boxes you
have areas you have columns there's
NeverEnding different ways on how you
can see the market I personally will
only and ever analyze the market on
candlesticks it is the most effective
and it is the simplest way on how you
can do it if you do not trade with
candlesticks you are simply not trading
correctly sometimes occasionally I will
analyze with the line chart because the
line chart is easier to identify Market
structure Market structure you can tell
if the market is bullish or the market
is bearish you can identify the trend
place an area of interest you just see
the real raw structure of the market
versus when you are on the Candlestick
chart you could get a little distracted
because of these big Wicks and
rejections and it could cause some
confusion but the importance is the
market structure and you can read that
to the bodies of the candlesticks if you
notice wherever the bodies of the
candlesticks are which I'm going to get
into detail now on how these
candlesticks actually work
where these bodies are is exactly where
the structure point is so it's just
simpler way of looking at the markets
without having all these candles sticks
next to that you have all the time
frames there is many different time
frames out there I personally only use a
weekly Daily 4 Hour 2 Hour 1 hour 30
minute 15 minutes and as you can see I
have a star in them cuz then they
favored it and leave them up here if I
want to add another time frame I just
put a star pops it up here if I don't
want it take off the star and it removes
it this plus sign and currency pair is a
different way on how to search up for a
pair exactly how we did earlier but for
me I rather just have to just type it
it's the exact same thing and you don't
have to click here now this is just
where your profile is and under all of
that are the different tools that you
can possibly use last time I wasted too
much time explaining all these
unnecessary tools which truthfully how
the hell do you even use this to
identify a trade like what the hell is
that it's impossible so to avoid wasting
time and bombarding you with unnecessary
information these are the only tools
that you will be needing the horizontal
line the horizontal aray the trend line
call out box rectangle brush Eclipse
text half long position sore position
head and shoulders and rotated rectangle
everything else that is inside of here
all these different patterns all these
different Elliot waves all these
different angles and Cycles has
absolutely no use and you will never be
profitable by using them they once again
how the hell does this tell you if the
market is going to go up or down this
looks like a greenhouse ever seen a
greenhouse where they grow tomatoes or
onions this is what that looks like that
is not going to make you profitable and
then moving down you have one of the
most important tools I would say is the
measuring tool this measuring tool
measures how much time something is and
how long in Pips something is I mainly
use it for the time so if you see as I
go to the right this little option here
is increasing because that is how much
time this Market moves for example this
Market from this point to where it is
now was 20 days and there was 14 bars if
we go from here to
here this Market moved from this point
from where this line is to where this
line is 99 days and it has 69 bars this
is a form of measuring time and Pips
pretty much this plus sign I've never
used everything under here I've never
used except this ey right here because
sometimes you could get a little lost if
you have a bunch of different drawings
on your chart and sometimes you just
want to see what the market looks like
without of them instead of having to
delete them you just simply remove all
the drawings and then you can put them
right back it's an easier way on how to
get a clear VIs visual of what the
market is doing this section over here I
don't know what the hell this is just a
bunch of random numbers that are always
moving whenever I'm moving the tool I
have no use for it down here you can see
that this is the date of where the
market is so if I were to go to this
candle stick right here I look at the
bottom that is Monday 13th January 25th
if I go over here Friday 22nd November
2024 just a way of measuring the time of
where the market is at that very point
and this is just what the value is
picture it as Bitcoin this is the price
of Bitcoin right now it's at
96,000 up here the high was
109,000 for the carency pairs it's the
exact same thing this is what the
currency pair is worth right now
0.627 and the little time under it is
how much time each Candlestick is left
per time frame that you are in for
example right now we are in the daily
time frame this daily time frame has 1
hour and 54 minutes left before it
closes what the 4 Hour has the exact
same time if I go to the 30 minutes 30
minute has about 23 minutes left before
this canvas closes and it's basically
never ending per each time frame this is
an
overall gist of what trading view is
very Advanced very straight to the point
only focusing on the things that you
need there's so much more on this
platform that I can spend hours talking
about and telling you why you don't need
it but what's the point in that all you
care about is how to analyze the market
correctly how to properly place your
trade and how to read the market you
don't need to know what the tools are
that's not going to help you how to read
the market so now that you understand
how trading view works I'm going to
explain to you how a Candlestick works
now keep in mind what you are seeing is
a direct representation of what the
market Market is doing in Candlestick
form what does that mean well let's say
right now you're a hunter and you're
going to go hunts in the woods
Everglades wherever Hunter hunts I've
never hunted in my life so I have no
idea but they say you're going to go
hunts in the woods and you are chasing
an elk you're following their foot
tracks these foot tracks is telling you
where the elk is going where this animal
is going is it going up a mountain is it
going going down a creek is it walking
in a straight line is it doing circles
it tells you exactly what the elk has
done if the elk has laid down if it took
a [__] you can see it in the trail
because it's literally telling you where
the elk is and where the elk is going
this is the exact same thing EUR USD is
the elk and this is the Trail of Euro
USD what we are doing is following the
trail of your USD but in candlestick
format you follow the tracks of an elk
because the hes are left on the ground
those are your candlesticks when you're
hunting and you can tell by looking at
the hoof if it's a male elk if it's a
big elk even is an elk it might be a
bear it might be in a really bad
situation but you can identify what
animal you are following when it comes
to the markets you could identify if
this Market is moving fast if this
Market is moving slow if this Market is
moving in the trend that you want is it
even trending you can identify
everything by Candlestick so whenever
the market is moving upwards the
candlesticks are blue whenever the
Candlestick are moving downwards the
candlesticks are red and I mean when
it's moving upwards that it's blue and
downwards when it's red because just
because a Candlestick is blue or red
does not mean that that is the trend of
the market does not mean that that's
where the market will be headed for the
rest of the hour the rest of the day the
rest of the week the rest of the month
that is just that current specific move
perfect example let's say an elk is
going up a mountain the elk is not going
to go up a mountain straight up because
on the way up to the mountain there's
probably trees there's probably big
boulders you have to go up and around
objects to then get to the top of the
mountain but there's times where the elk
had to go down to go up this is the
exact same thing here just because
there's some type of movements that move
downward and back up and downwards and
back up doesn't mean that every single
time it goes up or go down that it's
going to go in that direction
permanently there's an overall movement
and these minor retracements is just
part of the market doing its journey to
get to the overall point so the
candlesticks leave a trail and when a
Candlestick opens it has 1 hour 30
minutes 4 Hour whatever time frame you
are on to create that trail so let's go
to the 15 minute that we are in right
now now for example and this Candlestick
right now currently as we are speaking
it is creating
a push to the upside now if that
Candlestick has a retracement and it
starts moving back to the downside it
will leave a wick like how this one is
right here that is the Trail of that
Candlestick at that very moment as of
right now there's about 3 minutes left
before this Candlestick closes and as
soon as that Candlestick opens
it created a little move to the downside
so that Candlestick was red probably for
a couple seconds and then it kept
pushing up so you guys can see right
there the wick that that Candlestick has
already left is because the market was
all the way at that high point at one
point which is a couple seconds ago but
it started retracing a little bit so
this Wick is not confirmed into this
Candlestick does not close once this
Candlestick closes then that move is
100% certain but meanwhile the time is
running and the Candlestick is pushing
the Candlestick is not confirmed having
a wick or no Wick this Wick right here
is the trail that the Candlestick leaves
behind when there's a really really
really big wick that means that price
did not like that area the best example
that I could explain is if the elk was
coming back down it saw let's say a
potential shooter and it completely ran
up the mountain it didn't not like that
area that is kind of the direct
representation of what a wick is when it
comes to the market the market gets to a
certain point doesn't like it and then
it rejects it and each different
Candlestick creates their own Wicks
creates their own movements and have
their own meaning obviously the higher
the time frame the stronger and the more
respectable that Candlestick is a
Candlestick that takes 15 minutes to
form is not going to be anywhere near as
respected as a Candlestick that takes
one week to form or a day to form or 4
hours to form the higher the time frame
the more respected the Candlestick is
always keep that in mind so as you guys
can see there's about 15 seconds before
this Candlestick closes and I've seen
some crazy [__] in the past with like 3
seconds to close this Candlestick will
literally fly up or fly down so you can
never you can never trust these
candlesticks until it does not fully
close it is not a confirmation into the
C doesn't close believe me you do not
want to make that mistake so right there
you can see how couple of minutes ago it
was all the way up here it looked very
bullish and then now that it closed it
has closed with a rejection meaning that
this can now head to the downside now
once again I can't believe this
Candlestick that it's going to now
completely go to the downside because
there's still a whole 15 minutes this
can take 13 minutes being stuck here in
the last 3 minutes it has the move to
the upside you will never know exactly
what is going to happen and when when
these candlesticks are being formed but
bodies are the strength of it and the
Wicks are the trail of it remember that
now in order for you to execute these
trades you need to have your money
somewhere so you can execute these
trades back in the 80s if you were to
want to enter a trade you would have to
call a broker and be like hey I want to
enter a trade you will send the money
you will send the wire confirmation and
then they'll take the trade for you
nowadays we're in the 20 first century
this is a lot faster now and you can do
it within seconds but using a broker is
like using a bank account there's many
great bank accounts and then there's
also shitty bank accounts there's great
features on some and bad features on
others but there is trusted bank
accounts and in order for you to pay
somebody in order for you to pay for a
car in order for you to make your light
bill payment in order for you to pay for
your credit card you need to have a bank
account now a bank account is the same
exact thing as a a broker why because
this is where you're going to store your
money put it into the broker and when
you're in the broker and you go execute
a trade the broker will then deploy that
trade into the markets the broker is the
middleman in between you and the markets
they make sure your trade gets executed
on time and exactly where you want and
they make sure that your money is safe
same thing as the bank account the bank
account is the middle person in between
you and the person you want to pay they
make sure that your money is safe and
that you pay your person on time and
everything at well now there is hundreds
thousands of different Brokers out there
I don't believe there is a best broker I
believe that there is a trusted broker
this is the current broker that I use
right now which is lqh markets been
using it for a very long time my whole
entire Community uses it and it is an
option that I if I were to recommend
people to it would be this one if there
were to be a different option that I
would recommend I would but this is the
trusted one that I recommend there's
many out there that I'm sure that are
better
have better commissions they have better
Lots per sizing but this is the one that
I personally use I love it it is
offshore crypto in and out quick and
easy deposits leverage 1 to 500 and I
personally put in a lot of money and
I've taken out a lot of money the only
con that I would say is that this broker
right now if you are in the US and you
trying to access it it simply will not
let you you got to turn on a VPN and
then it will will let you access this
broker but if you for whatever reason
cannot access this broker with a VPN and
you want another us version broker of
this I'll leave the link in the
description for that broker as well so
after you create an account with lq this
is kind of what the inside will look
like this is an account that I created
probably like two months ago with some
students on how to actually create an
account deposit money do the whole nine
with it and this is basically your
portal so if you were to have a bank
account with the Chase Bank of America
or whatever Bank in your country this is
the inside of your bank account this is
where you're going to be able to see how
much money you have the different types
of accounts how much money you have
available and all of your transaction
histories now this is just the bank
account the bank account is where your
money is stored now there is a platform
where you're going to be able to send
the money and execute trades onto the
real markets now the simplest way that I
can put this analogy and I'm I'm going
to use a US version because I have US
Bank and I think the majority of the
audience is in the US let's say we were
to have a bank with Chase Bank and you
want to send money to somebody else's
Chase Bank you can use a couple
different platforms you can use uh zel
you can use cash app you can use VMO you
can use PayPal you can use wire
transactions all of these different
platforms is where the bank puts the
money into and uses this platform to
execute that transaction and send it to
someone else this is the exact same
thing this broker is a platform where
then it's going to be connected to
metatrader where on a metatrader you're
going to then be able to execute your
trade whether you want to buy a trade
sell a trade so on metatrader is not the
platform where you're going to be able
to withdraw the money from PayPal cash
zel they never have your money they're
just the midlan of the people that get
your money and put it into the market
once the money is made it goes back from
that platform into the bank account so
now that you understand all of this it's
time to actually execute a trade right
now we're going to execute a trade
together exactly how I would so I'm
going to take you through the full top
down analysis the confluences that I'll
use and then the entry signal going to
take you guys through executing a trade
and even closing a trade I'm going to
show you how in the matter of 10 minutes
I can probably make a 100 bucks like
that so let's get started the first
thing I do when it comes to analyzing a
market is going to be identifying the
trend for example let's say we have this
market right here this Market is a
perfect example of a market that many
Traders would make a very big mistake on
many Traders would approach this market
and think that this Market is currently
bearish or they would think that it's
bullish the correct answer is that this
Market is currently bullish if we were
to look at the market structure on this
Market this is how it would look higher
high higher low and higher high this is
the structure of this Market higher high
higher low higher high and now we are
creating structure I know many of you
might get confused and consider this a
higher low I personally do not consider
anything that has one Candlestick as a
point of structure you need at least two
candlesticks for the market to then
create that proper Market structure so
you can consider it an elbow and then
where the snake would have turned if
there is some confusion for whatever
reason you grab the head of the snake
right here and on your way back you ask
yourself is this where the snake turned
or is that a little log on a road and
then it just continues to go through it
that's a little log in the road the
snake never really change direction at
any given point so for example this
Market would be a great Market I would
be interested in simply because we're
starting off with the weekly bullish
next I would go down to the Daily time
frame and many Traders would make the
exact same mistake at this point here
you would probably think that this
Market is either bullish or bearish so I
actually want to test you real quick go
ahead and pause the video and let me
know if you think this Market is bullish
or bearish and then I'm going to correct
you on it so this Market is actually
bullish this Market went from creating
higher high higher low higher high
higher low higher high lower low lower
high High lower low lower high lower low
and now this is a higher high and this
is a potential higher low this is how
this Market structure looks so if we
were to look at this on the line chart
because we obviously use the Candlestick
chart once again to look at the actual
way the market represents it but then if
we were to look at it on the line chart
you can see that all of these lines are
on the body of the structure points so
you see for example that body right
there if we take off the no Gap
candlesticks you notice it's where the
line chart has created a point of
structure point of structure is exactly
the same as the bodies you notice right
here these bodies you take out the
candlesticks point of structure on the
retest of the bodies and then you notice
it's the point of structure the Wicks
are just the history it's the trail of
where the market was but it's not where
the market actually stood and closed at
simplest example is it's kind of like
the trail of when the elk or the bear is
walking through snow and it kind of
leaves like that drag but it's not where
it actually left the footprint this Wick
is the exact same thing as that so when
I'm looking for the structure I'm
looking for the bodies of the
candlesticks I never actually go to the
line chart because if I go to the line
chart I get too many unnecessary Market
structure points that it really doesn't
count I would never count this right
here as a structure point but if look at
it on the line chart it does so you can
use a line chart to kind of practice
identifying the higher high and higher
low but I would never use it to
determine if the market is bullish or
bearish simply because it's not going to
give you the most accurate way that the
market is actually moving you want to do
it based off of the Candlestick that
this Market is showing you so this right
here if you notice it has two
candlesticks as a a pullback you have
one Candlestick and then the other red
Candlestick this a very clean elbow to
me I would count this as a lower low
because this right here would be the
lower high and then this right here
would be the lower low if I were to look
at this market like this and this Market
instead of continuing to the upside and
it would have created a big bearish move
to the downside for example like this
that right there would be a very
significant lower high point in the
market this would have been a lower low
this would have been a lower high and
then this would have been a lower low
obviously that's not the case scenario
Market headed to the upside but the
principle still applies and this is
something that a lot of Traders would
make a mistake when analyzing the
markets they'll either Overlook it or
underlook it so this Market is bullish
as well so we have the weekly bullish
and now the daily time frame bullish
remember that we need a minimum of two
time frames in sync in order to execute
a trade so now that we understand that
the weekly and the daily is bullish now
then we go to the 4H hour on the 4H hour
time frame let's take this test once
again it's okay to make mistakes it is
part of the game this is how you learn
is this Market bullish or bearish pause
the video take your time and select so
you probably made another mistake and
it's totally fine because I'm here to
teach you I'm here to help you this
Market is actually bearish so I want you
to know exactly why this Market is
bearish not because you just made an
assumption this is a higher high we then
shifted obviously the structure in here
lower high lower low lower high lower
low lower high lower low lower high and
there's multiple structure in here long
story short lower high and lower low
this is how this Market structure is
currently looking at it went from
creating higher highs and higher lows
being bullish to then shifting to being
bearish so this Market is currently
bearish this right here at this point is
the lower high and then this point over
here is then the lower low
so we have weekly bullish daily bullish
and 4-Hour bearish we just need two
consecutive time frames in sync to
execute a trade meaning weekly or daily
or daily and 4H hour in this case we
have the weekly and the daily which is
good now we then move on to the next
point which is area of interest because
you can have the trend in your direction
but if you are not near an area of
Interest the trade simply does not make
sense for example let's say we're
looking at Bitcoin right now for example
right and Bitcoin Let's Pretend as soon
as it created this High move right here
as soon as it broke alltime highs and
created alltime Highs at 104 340 yes the
weekly could be bullish because this
would be the higher high this would be
the higher low daily time frame would be
bullish as well this over here would
then be the higher high then this would
be the higher low and then the 4H hour
time frame would be bullish as well this
over here would be the higher high and
this would be the higher low oh wow you
have three consecutive time frames in
sync that means that you should take the
trade immediately no this is actually
probably one of the worst trades that
you can possibly take because if
everything is at a high point where is
your takeprofit going to be where is
there going to be a move for price to
reach a recent point of structure for
then you to place your takeprofit
there's none because price is at a very
high point or vice versa if price is at
a very low point if everything is
bullish and everything is at the higher
high at the highest point that is not a
market you want to be trading there is
no high probability trade setup in that
market right there that is actually a
market you want to stay away from you
want to execute markets that are bullish
and have the trend in your favor but
have an area of interest for example if
you are a investor and you want to put
money into Bitcoin you're not going to
put money at the highest point you're
going to wait for what I like to call a
discount you're going to wait for price
to have some type of a retracement and
as soon as it has that retracement SL
discount is where then you will enter
and this retracement and discount is
also known as price retracing to the
area of Interest once price comes back
to this area of Interest then you can
execute your trade and then here once
you go execute your trade is where then
it's going to actually make sense in
order for you to place your long
position if you do not have have a
discount there is going to be no place
on where you can properly place your
stop- loss and where you can properly
place your take profit and we can just
simply play this forward as a quick very
simple example here price had the
retracement had the discount back to the
area of Interest all of these three
things are the same thing just set in a
different way and as soon as it had a
retrace it back into the area of
interest you can see how price then
decides to go back right up to the high
now this is a very simple example of you
simply waiting for price to come back to
the area of interest if price is not at
the area of interest you cannot execute
a trade if you can write down a note
that is very important big and bold
letters it would be this one if price is
not at the area of interest you do not
take the trade you want to wait for a
discount there's no discount there is no
trade so back to the market that we were
analyzing we can very clearly identify
that we can see on the weekly time frame
that we are indeed at an area of
interest if you notice this area of
Interest has 1 2 3 four rejections from
this area a valid area of Interest
consists of three taps or more it can be
three levels of resistance three levels
of support one resistance to support One
support to resistance one and one and
one doesn't matter as long as there's a
minimum of three TAPS at this area this
is a valid area area of interest if you
notice right here this would be then one
tap this would be two Taps then this
would be three and then this would be
four if we were to obviously flip this
chart around it'd be the exact same
thing we would have three levels of
support one level of resistance we have
four taps this is a valid area of
Interest which leads me to understand
that now we are then ready to look for
the next thing because we are bullish on
two time frames frames and we are at an
area of Interest all we need in order
for us to enter this trade is simply an
entry signal and after our entry signal
which I'm going to explain now we then
have to properly place our stop loss
then we go calculate our risk then we
execute a trade just because you have a
trend area of interest and entry signal
doesn't mean you go execute the trade no
you have to properly place your stop
loss at the correct point then you risk
on how much you want to risk then you
execute the trade this is where a lot of
Traders make mistakes and they end up
blowing the account and losing a lot of
money so what is an entry signal that I
would look for well one of my favorite
formations is engulfing candlesticks and
engulfing candlesticks leads me to
understand that that current price is
eating the previous price meaning that
it is stronger than whatever is to the
left if something is engulfing something
it's bigger and stronger than what's
next to it so if you have a bullish
engulfing candle stick while the trend
is bullish at an area of Interest this
is the perfect entry signal that you can
possibly ask for to execute a trade and
that's exactly what we have right here
right here we have a bullish engulfing
Candlestick right at this area of
Interest we have a doe rejection
Candlestick which is also one of my
favorite rejection candlesticks which I
pretty much use all of the time only
once they are at the area of interest if
it's not on an area of Interest it
really doesn't mean anything to me and
then after that we have some type of
continuation for me personally I
probably would not take this trade where
price is currently right now which is at
this High I probably would have entered
at this point right here but for this
trade example we can still enter the
trade here and I can almost guarantee
you that we will still make money so
since now we just analyzed a trade with
our Trend our area of interest and our
entry signal let's go take a trade so
let's head back to lq Marcus where we
are going to create a quick account just
to show you guys how quick it is for us
to be able to actually execute a
position so now we're back at lq where
we are going to create a new account so
we just take a trade together when you
go create your new account you can get a
commission free standard Pro
institutional just for example purposes
we're going to use standard account
we're going to create with a 1 to 500
leverage and it's going to be a $10,000
account soon as you create accounts
you're going to see a popup where the
demo accounts was successfully created
for you so now is where you actually go
execute the trade on metatrader and if
you were see that I literally just got
my email right now where it shows that
my credentials to log in to my
metatrader 5 are already set all you
have to do is create an account with the
broker and then the broker will create
an account for you on metat Trader which
is where you're actually going to
execute the position remember lq is like
the bank and then PayPal is like metat
tra so I'm going to start screen
recording here on my phone and we're
going to Simply log into this account I
literally just got the email going to go
right straight to my email and I'm going
to log in so I'm going to copy my
account ID we're going to go to
metatrader 5 we're going to log in to a
new server I'm going to place the
account login I'm going to go back copy
the master
password and as soon as I copy the
master password it should log me in
immediately and you can see that our
account has been officially created with
$10,000 so now we go back to trading
View and we're ready to take the trade
so let's go execute the trade on GBP CAD
we search it up GBP no GBP AUD so here
on GBP AUD we would simply come here
click trade and then we're ready to buy
it ready 3 2 1 and you were about to
make the biggest mistake that 90% of
Traders make they have not placed their
stop loss and they have not properly
calculated the risk that they want in
your account this is a huge mistake that
Traders make and it will completely
determine your results in trading if
you're going to be successful or not you
need a proper stop loss and you need to
have risk management if you are not
ready to do this you are not ready to be
a profitable Trader and I want to
express the importance of this because
if you don't do this you will not be
profitable so let's let's not make that
mistake and let's go to my effects book
position size calculator where we're
going to type in the pair that we're
trading which is going to be let's say
GBP AUD we type it in we put the account
size which for this example it's
$10,000 and let's say we want to risk
$11,000 on this trade our stop loss is
exactly we make our stop loss a little
bit tighter our stop loss would then be
32 Pips so let's calculate here
a 32 pip stop loss once you click
calculate it tells you your exact lot
size you should be taking so this would
be a five Lots on the account now that
we properly have our stop loss number
and we have our proper risk management
then we go to GBP CAD we click trade up
here we will then put five lots and then
we will put our stoploss number which is
1.97 358 1.9 7 5 no
358 and then we will click buy but
before we click buy I want to let you
guys know why we never put a takeprofit
we don't ever put a takeprofit because
it completely goes again my slogan
called set and forget we set and forget
to trade when we are in it it either
hits our stop loss or our takeprofit we
never place a takeprofit because we
always want to maximize and let a
winning trade continue to be a winning
trade especially when you're you're
trading with the higher time frames and
you're trading with the weekly trading
with the daily and you're trading with
the trend this move should continue to
happen for 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 days at a
time and by you putting a take profit
you're putting a cap on how much money
you can make you always want to put a
cap on how much money you can lose but
never on how much money you can make
because remember losing is inevitable in
trading and the only way you make back
those losses is by winning and if you
can maximize your wins by analyzing a
profitable trade setup all you have to
do is just simply let the market do its
thing continue going with the trend and
it's making you continuous passive
income without you doing absolutely
anything else you're not adding any more
risk and you're not analyzing any more
trades so we never place a takeprofit we
always place a stop loss so before this
Market takes off which it already is
we're just going to click buy at this
moment and then we execute the trade so
as of right now we are negative about
$141 because we are taking a trade at
the worst time possible it is 4:38 p.m.
EST meaning that the spreads right now
are very high so you can see right here
in the quote section how next to GBP AUD
and the time down below which is 3857
says 46 there's a 46 spread on this
market right now meaning that it is very
very expensive to execute a trade so the
broker is going to charge you a lot more
than it would charge you if it were to
be a couple of hours ago why because
banks are closing around the world and
half of the world is basically already
offline so the odds of you entering a
trade at this time are not probable
think about it as if you were to go eat
food at a Chipotle when it's like 30
minutes before it close you're getting
the worst rice the worst chicken the
worst beans you don't want to get the
last food that's in the bottom of the
barrel it tastes terrible this is
similar but with money because simply
everything is closed and there is no
liquidity right now things start to pick
back up probably in the next 30 minutes
to 45 minutes after the markets close
because then a new session kicks in so
from here to then is literally the worst
time to execute a trade and I
strategically did this to show you guys
on what it is to execute a trade at this
time if I were to execute a trade
literally an hour ago I would probably
already be into profit but since this is
for a educational purpose video this is
a demo account no big deal but I want
you guys to understand never ever
execute a trade around this time all
right so now the trade is at NE $37 the
fact that I am even about to be in
profit in just under 10 minutes at this
time in the market is literally
ridiculous this is like if Chipotle
would have brought out 5 minutes before
closing fresh rice fresh chicken fresh
beans this is unseen in the market well
I you can say the market went back down
a little bit it's probably going to take
about another another 15 20 minutes so
market update probably 7 minutes later
we are literally in the worst possible
time to be even looking at the medr you
know I'm going to show you one of my
other accounts editors please edit my
information where currently I am
floating $100,000 in profit right now
this is a challenge account you saw how
I was just $100,000 in profit and it
went down to 80 because at 5:00 sharp
the spreads go absolutely insane so you
can see here how the spreads are pretty
much around the same but the slippage is
ridiculous right now if I were to close
this trade right now it doesn't matter
if you're in the best broker in the
world if you have whatever type of
account you will get immense amount of
slippage if you notice we're right
around the exact point on where we enter
the market and we're more negative than
we even started why because of the
spread and slippage the market has but
since this is a demo account for this
example purposes I will be closing at
this point right here just to show you
guys how to close your position you tap
the phone and then you just click close
position right here soon as you click
that close position you're going to see
it in your history section you're going
to be able to see how much time you were
in the trade and your end results after
commission after the fees everything is
pretty standard right there right in
front of you and for those of you guys
that don't know what spread and what
slippage and what commissions are think
about it the fees that the bank has to
charge you whenever you go pay
transaction on on PayPal PayPal charges
you four or five bucks a couple bucks
that's how PayPal makes money by
charging you a fee when you go to the
bank the bank has monthly recurring fees
by making sure your account is active
that can also be seen as the spread or
the commission same thing as when you
use a credit card and then you have
interest that is could be the same thing
as swap so whenever you hold a trade for
longer than 24 hours you get charge swap
you also get charged commission
everything is just in fees on when you
enter the trade when you exit the trade
and how long you hold it for truthfully
if you want me to be honest the fees are
one unavoidable they have no direct
relation if if it's going to let you be
profitable or not and they are
completely irrelevant to how much money
you are risking I like to look at it
like the 2% fee it's just the cost of me
making money or obviously losing money
so if I'm looking to risk 100 bucks on a
trade I'd be risking 102 $ if I'm making
money instead of me making $100 I'm
making
$98 so I can hold it a little bit longer
so I can make up for the fees but
realistically 2% is not going to make or
break anything in your trade it's part
of the game it's inevitable and trust me
I pay very very high fees when I trade
and trust me I pay multiple five figures
if not within the month six figures in
just fees because it is directly
correlated on how much money you risk
and how much money you make I don't know
about you but if I make half a million
dollars in one trade I don't mind paying
$115,000 in fees a lot of Brokers and a
lot of markets out there they're
facilitating this for you to make this
money if you're going to drop them a
quarter or a dime they can have that
just give me the big stack of cash and
what I love about this video is that I
have been extremely transparent and
giving you guys the realistic journey of
a Trader what it is that you have to do
when you get to the market how you
should approach the market how you
should properly execute a trade manage a
trade this this is something that it's
almost like a day in the life of a
Trader this is exactly how you should be
trading and there should not be any
add-on indicators there should not any
add-on platforms any add-on risk tools
this is all you really need to execute
the market analyze it correctly and make
money I've been as transparent and as
direct as I possibly could happen so
picture this as if you were to have just
bought a car the sales guys is going to
tell you the car has x amount of Miles
the car has x amount of color interior
and the condition of the car but
realistically after you drive off of the
parking lot with that car if there's a
check engine light or the car needs an
oil change salesman has no idea what the
hell how he's going to do that that's
what I'm doing I'm getting down deep and
dirty I'm telling you exactly how to do
your own oil change how to properly
rotate your tires how to properly check
your engine make sure that everything is
good your transmission your AC your
power steering I'm giving you the ins
and outs of your whole entire vehicle
which is your trading plan which is the
Market that is going to get you to
success I'm not just selling you a dream
and letting you go and deal with the
problems later no I'm letting you know
exactly what's going on and you're fully
aware of it at every single second that
you're doing it and if at this point in
the video you still want to see more you
should go check out the 4H hour video
this 4H hour video is everything that I
taught you today but a bit more slow a
bit more in detail I went into a lot
more explanation on finding tuning
things that truthfully you might might
need as a beginner and exactly how this
video was free so was that video there
is so much value in that video that it's
literally taking Traders from 0 to 50%
that time gap of 0 to 50% took me 2
years it can literally take you a 4our
video so once again this is all
absolutely for free I ask for nothing in
return all I ask for is for you to hit
that like And subscribe button if you're
enjoying these videos make sure to leave
a comment as well and I personally
highly recommend you go watch that
4-Hour video video because if you really
really want to get the deep down details
make sure you go click up here watch the
video and trust me won't regret it thank
you guys for being part of this video
I'll see you in the next one